Guide to the Papers of Alice Virginia Keliher 1918-1995 MC 139
New York University Archives
- Series I: Printed Material
  - Subseries C: Teachers College.Contributions to Education Series (1925-1946) and other books
    - Ratner, Joseph. Intelligence in the Modern World. John Dewey's Philosophy., 1939 (Box 9)
    - Riley, Clara M. D. and Epps, Frances M. J. Head Start in Action., 1967 (Box 9)
    - Pratt,Caroline. I Learn from Children., 1948 (Box 9)
    - Keliher, Alice. A Critical Study of Homogeneous Grouping., 1931 (Box 9)
    - Sprague Mitchell, Lucy and Co-Authors. Another Here and Now Story Book., 1937 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Philosophy of Education., 1958 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John and Evelyn. Schools of Tomorrow., 1962 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Human Nature and Conduct., 1922 (Box 9)
    - Dewey on Education, edited by Martin S. Dworkin, 1959 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Experience and Education., 1963 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. The Public and its Problems., 1927 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Logic, the Theory of Inquiry., 1921 (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I. Continuous Learning., 1951 (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I. Childhood Ed. Probing Ideas and Improving Practices, Grouping; Apr-60., 1960 (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I. Childhood Ed. Vol. 36,Number 5; Jan. 1960. (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I. Childhood Ed. Vol. 39, Number 8; Apr-63., 1963 (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I. Childhood Ed. Ways of Grouping;April 1968. (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I. That All Children May Learn We Must Learn., 1971 (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I. Testing and Evaluation: New Views., 1975 (Box 9)
    - McFadden,Dennis. Planning for Action., 1972 (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I. Continuous Learning., 1951 (Box 9)
    - Borg, Walter R. Ability Grouping in the Public Schools., 1966 (Box 9)
    - N.J.E.A. Review. They Chose Cultural Pluralism., 1972 (Box 9)
    - Franseth, Jane. Does Grouping Make A Difference in Pupil Learning?, 1962 (Box 9)
    - The Elementary School Journal, by the Univ. of Chicago Press; March, 1966. (Box 9)
    - Center for Law and Education. Inequality in Education;Jul-73., 1973 (Box 10)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058108 7
    - California State Dept. of Ed. The Education of Emotionally Handicapped Children; Mar-61., 1961 (Box 10)
    - Wrightstone, J. Wayne. Class Organization for Instruction., 1957 (Box 10)
    - Plaut, Richard L. Blueprint for Talent Searching., 1957 (Box 10)
    - Cox, E.A. The 11 Plus Preparation Book., 1958 (Box 10)
    - Blishen,Edward. Minus 11 Plus., 1957 (Box 10)
    - N.E.A. Educational Leadership. What is Teaching?; Dec. 1961. (Box 10)
    - N.E.A. Research Bulletin.Volume 40, Number 2; May-62., 1962 (Box 10)
    - N.E.A. Multi-Age Grouping: Enriching the Learning Environment., 1968 (Box 10)
    - The Education Digest; Mar-62., 1962 (Box 10)
    - Olson, Willard C. The Improvement of Human Relations in the Classroom; Mar-46., 1946 (Box 10)
    - Murchison, Carl,editor. Genetic Psychology Monographs. Child Behavior, Animal Behavior, and Comparative Psychology., 1936 (Box 10)
    - Teacher's College Record; Mar-31., 1931 (Box 10)
    - Winnicott, D.W. The Child and the Family., undated (Box 11)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058109 5
    - A. C. E. I. Dauntless Women in Childhood Education., 1856-1931 (Box 11)
    - Mearns, Hughes. Creative Youth,How a School Environment Set Free the Creative Spirit., 1927 (Box 11)
    - Lewis, Richard and Kimura, Haruna. There are Two Lives:Poems of Children of Japan., 1970 (Box 11)
    - Langer,Walter. Psychology and Human Living with a forward by AVK., 1937 (Box 11)
    - Commission of Human Relations, AVK Chairman. Thicker than Water, Stories of Family Life., 1939 (Box 11)
    - Commission of Human Relations. Society and Family Life., 1937 (Box 11)
    - Featherstone, Joseph. Schools where Children Learn., 1973 (Box 11)
    - Keliher, Alice. Talks with Teacher. Foreward by Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt, 1958 (Box 11)
    - Keliher, Alice. Life and Growth, 1938 (Box 11)
    - Picture Fact Books Series, AVK, Editor, undated (Box 11)
    - Doctors at Work, 1941, 1946 (Box 11)
    - Retail Sales Workers, 1941 (Box 11)
    - Library Workers, 1940 (Box 11)
    - Farm Workers, 1940 (Box 11)
    - Textile Workers, 1939 (Box 11)
    - News Workers, 1939 (Box 11)
    - Air Workers, 1938, 1939, 1942 (Box 11)
    - Nurses at Work, 1939, 1946 (Box 11)
    - Household Workers, 1941 (Box 11)
    - Machinists at Work, 1941, 1946 (Box 11)
    - Office Workers, 1940 (Box 11)
    - Movie Workers, 1939 (Box 11)
    - Railroad Workers, 1941 (Box 11)
    - Radio Workers, 1940 (Box 11)
    - Picture Fact Books Pamphlet, undated (Box 11)
- Series II: Personal Publications and Files
  This series includes personalarticles, correspondence with other educators and scholars, index card collections, personal notes,materials for her books, misc. publications and a rather complete collection of her personalarticles (Box 14). There are scrapbooks, photo books and an authograph book in the same box.
  bar code#: 3 1142 0405
  - NEA Journal (National Education Assoc.) AVK articles, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058110 3
  - Progressive Education. AVK articles, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Teacher's College Correspondence and New College, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Experimental Schools, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Reprints of AVK articles, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Isaacs, Susan and Montague, Ashley's articles about early childhood ed., undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Attorney General conferences, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Index cards collection. Includes: "Who Speaks for Our Children" speech. Notes on Harvard Review Issue, Feb. 73.About perspectives on inequality. Information ordered A-Z., undated,1973 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Kindergarten Research, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Langer, Walter. Articles and correspondence, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - NYA for New Jersey. Program coordinated by AVK, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - History of the Center for Human Relations Studies 1947-1956 by H. Harry Giles. At school of Ed. NYU., undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Citizen's Committee on Children of N.Y., 1945-1952 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Citizen's Committee on Children of N.Y. Board and Executive Minutes/Membership, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Citizen's Committee on Children of N.Y. Founding, 1944-1946 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Freud Clinic-Notes, Blind, AVK visits, etc., undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Utah University, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Hartford Public Schools. Annual Reports, Corresp., undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Jersey City College, Correspondence, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Wheelock College,Correspondence, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - NYU Correspondence, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Mississippi Workshop, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Refugees. Corresp. with people Keliher helped escape the Nazis (i.e. Walter Langer), undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Mainstreaming in Early Childhood ed., 1977 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - White House conference. Planning Committee, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058111 1
  - White House conference. AVK Chairman--Section III Mobilization and War, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1958-1959 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Child Development Manuscript, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Israel. Pamphlets from Kibbutz and course for kindergarten teachers and supervisors, 1972-1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Tucson General Hospital Foundation, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - The Progressive Ed. Assoc. incl. AVK speech, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Draft, AVK--A Critical Study of Homogeneous Grouping., undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Clippings on Grouping, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Book on Grouping--Materials, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Book on Grouping-Draft/Part I, Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Book on Grouping-Draft/Part II, Chapters 6-9, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Book on Grouping-Draft/Part III, Misc. Notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Freud, Anna. Correspondence with AVK. Includes photographs, and Senn, Burnstein, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Freud, Sigmund. Clippings and papers., undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Chisholm, G.B. "The Reestablishment of Peacetime Society.", undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - AVK Book Draft: Children at School. Tentative table of contents (only to be followed until Chap. V), preface to chap. II., undated (Box 13, Folder 17.A)
  - Children at School. Chap. III-VI, undated (Box 13, Folder 17.B)
  - Children at School. Chap. XVII. Organizing for Living in the Classroom. Child Development and the Elementary School Program, undated (Box 13, Folder 17.C)
  - Ms. Keliher's Publications in the Education Digest, undated (Box 14)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058112 9
  - Play's the Thing, Vol. I, Number 5, March 1936. Reported from the Junior-Senior High School Clearing House, X,330-33;February, 1936 (Box 14)
  - What Shall We Do About Hatred, Vol. V, Number 4; December, 1939 (Box 14)
  - The Kind of Parents Teachers Like, Vol. XVI, Number 3; November, 1950, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Environment for Learning for Today's Children, Vol. XXVIII, Number 6; February, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Effective Learning and Teacher-Pupil Ratio, Vol. XXXII, Number 5; January, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Do We Push Children?, Vol. XXVI, Number 6; February, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice. "Community Neglect of Children" in: The Journal for Educational Sociology; January, 1947 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice. "Reaching the Individual as a Person" in:Individualizing Education. Assoc. for Childhood Education Intl., 1962 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Chairman of Commission on Human Relations,Progressive Education Assoc. "Human Relationships and the Progressive School Program" in:The Contribution of Progressive Education and the Exceptional Child of the Child Research Clinic of the Woods Schools, A Private School for Exceptional Children, Langhorne, PA;May,1937 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Project Chairman. A Follow-Up Study of Graduates of the Fifth-Year Program of Teacher Education at New York University, 1952-1953 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, "Do We Push Children?" in: Don't Push Me. The Assoc. for Childhood Education International, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Visiting Professor."Effective Learning and Teacher Pupil Ratio." Wheelock College, Boston; Sept., 1966 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice. "Human Relations--A Community Check List." Social Progress. Vol. X X X V, No. 6. Dept. of Social Ed. and Action of the Board of Christian Ed. of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.; February,1945 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice. "Children, Schools and War." A Cooperative Report by Students from a course in Elementary Education. School of Education, N. Y. U.; Summer, 1942. (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice. "Creating a Good Environment for Learning." Education for American Freedom. Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development, 1954 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Chairman. Citizens Committee on Children of New York City, Inc. Citizens Look at their Schools, A Report, 1947 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Chairman. "Films in Human Relations Education" in The Human Relations Series of Films. Commission on Human Relations, 1939 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, "Are We Recognizing Individual Differences in Children?." In Can Children, Do Children Read?. Kent University Bulletin. Kent, Ohio; Dec.,1955 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, "The Grouping Question-1930 to 1962... In Toward Effective Grouping." Assoc. for Childhood ed. Intl. (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Editor and Co-Author."Report on Home Responsibility." National Conference on Prevention and Control of Juvenile Delinquency; Nov. 20-23, 1946 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Chairman. Children Absent from School. Citizens Committee on Children of New York City, Inc./unittitle>, 1949 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Chairman. Society and Family Life/Tentative, Experimental Form, Parts I and II. Commission on Human Relations, Progressive Education Association, 1937 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice, Chairman. Life and Growth/Tentative,Experimental Form. Commission on Human Relations, Progressive Education Association, 1937 (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice. Recruitment,Selection and Guidance of Students Preparing for Leadership. Teacher's College Record; Jan-52, undated (Box 14)
  - Keliher, Alice,"Restoring the Arts to the Kindergarten.", 1968 (Box 14)
  - Pamphlets and Books in which Ms. Keliher was somehow involved or mentioned., undated (Box 14)
  - Wheelock Alumnae Quarterly; Fall 1967 (Box 14)
  - Teacher's College Record; January, 1900 (Box 14)
  - Education for Today and Tomorrow. A Report of a Survey of the Plainview and Old Bethpage Central School District #4. Center for School Services. School of Education. N.Y.U., 1957 (Box 14)
  - Who's Who of American Women, Ms. Keliher mentioned on page 618., 1966-1967 (Box 14)
  - Encyclopedia of Educational Research. Presented by the American Educational Research Assoc. to Ms. Keliher in recognition of services rendered in the preparation of this volume., undated (Box 14)
  - Progressive Education Advances. Report on a program to educate American youth for present-day living, 1938 (Box 14)
  - The Education Digest. Vol. X X V I, Number 5; Jan., 1961 (Box 14)
  - Assoc. for Childhood Ed. Intl. Basic Human Values for Childhood Ed., 1962 (Box 14)
  - Personal Scrapbooks and Photo Albums:, undated (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook with Clippings on Handicapped Children, 1973-1977 (Box 14)
  - Personal Publications and Memorabilia, undated (Box 14)
  - Autograph Book, 1900-1953 (Box 14)
  - Photo Book. Retirement from the N. J. Helping Teachers; 11-May-64, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Photo Book. Summer Class--Univ. at Hawaii, Honolulu, 1952 (Box 14)
- Series III: Work-Related Correspondence and Other Files (1935-1985)
  The correspondence is orderedalphabetically. The files are miscellaneous and kept in original order. They includebibliographies, magazines, information on the Head-Start program, files on Gesell, Kilpatrick,Zirbes and Frank that include correspondence, articles and clippings. There are also files onevery college where she taught.
  - A-B, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058113 7
  - C-D, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - E-F (includes the Texas Federation Correspondence), undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - G-H (Incl. Pamela A. Hanson Rich Correspondence and successful story of going back to school as a mother and wife), undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - I-J (incl. Jackson, Schuyler Thompson School), 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - K-L (incl. news of Ms. Keliher), undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - M-N (incl. correspondence on Nixon-Watergate issue), undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - O-P, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Q-R, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - S-T (incl. Spellman articles), undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - U-V, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - W-X-Y-Z (incl. Elizabeth Yates corresp.), undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - B-Other Files, undated (Box 15, Folder 12a)
  - AVK honors, biographies, and awards, 1935-1979 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - AVK-speeches and papers, 1962-1970 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - AVK-project Head Start, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - AVK--The Head Start Pattern--A Doll For All Children, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - (Book) Role of the Regional Training Officer. Related to the Head-Start project (1966). (Box 15)
  - Student Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Murphy, Lois. The Ways Children Learn ( No. 1-4), undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Girard College Case (incl. orphans' court publications, 1885), undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Misc. pamphlets: Handbook for Kindergarten. Ann J. Kellogg School, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Indian Education (includes a paper by AVK: "The Kindergarten to Third Grade Program, A Time to Change")., 1971 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Proposal to expand early childhood ed. for American Indians. AVK a member of the project, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Acoma conference. Bureau of Indian Affairs and Tribal- PCDP (Parent-Child Development Programs) related info. and AVK speeches, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Programs-clippings on AVK personal interest, 1929-1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058114 5
  - Bibliographies AVK recommends, 1955-1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Bibliographies AVK recommends, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Thinking Kit. by Pace (Parents and Child Education) with lots of quotes from AVK, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - C D A--Child Development Associate--Related to Day Care, 1970-1986 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - N.A.E.Y.C (National Assoc. for the Education of Young Children) incl. Listen to the Children, 1926-1977 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - AVK project for a book on her life and that of other important people includes autobiography and photos related to project and table of contents., undated (Box 16, Folder 8. A)
  - The Revolutionaries: Parker, Dewey and Marietta Johnson. Plus related info. and quotes from La Guardia., undated (Box 16, Folder 8. B)
  - Margaret McMillan, Laura Zirbes, Arnold Gesell, Lawrence Frank, undated (Box 16, Folder 8. C)
  - William Heard Kilpatrick, Eleanor Roosevelt and Lucy Sprague Mitchell, undated (Box 16, Folder 8. D)
  - Arnold Gesell articles and correspondence, undated (Box 16, Folder 8. E)
  - Kilpatrick correspondence, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Kilpatrick copies and pictures, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Kilpatrick, misc. letters and articles, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Zirbes, Laura. Kent State Univ. Letters and articles both on Zirbes and AVK's retirement, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Barbara Biber and the Bank Street School of Education. Frank, book containing letters of appreciation to him and portrait, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Frank, correspondence with AVK; and Frank's articles, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Frank, Lawrence--materials, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Dewey, John--materials, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Alabama College, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058115 2
  - Alabama College, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Alabama College, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Alabama College summer school, bulletins, Montevallo Project, and miscellaneous materials, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Miles--Rear Admiral, U.S. Navy, corresp., undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Hill, Patty. Studies on Kindergarten, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Human Relations series of films. Includes articles by AVK and listings of pedagogic films, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Misc. manuscripts--to process, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Olson charts, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - AZ-A S C P. incl. back to basics, articles by AVK. Manuscripts, research, and clippings on child development and energy saving, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Misc. speeches draft, notes and materials on language development, lights on education project,learning that lasts (AVK article), and early ed. changes, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Children on Tranquilizers, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Civilian Defense, Volunteer Office-- A Program in Child Care, Development, and Protection, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Day Care Bill, Brademas Hearings, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Encyclopedia of Educational Research, excerpts, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Child Study--AVK articles published on Child Study Assoc. of America's Issues, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Education Digest, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Educational Leadership, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Grade Teacher, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Journal of Educational Sociology, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Childhooded. AVK articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Mental Hygiene, AVK articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Junior-Senior Clearing House, AVK article: "Play's the Thing,", 1936 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - March of Dimes, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Wheelock Alumnae Quarterly, AVK articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Parent-Teacher magazine, AVK articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Parent Education, AVK articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Publisher contacts, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Infantile Paralysis, National Foundation of. Includes photographs of polio meeting in Warm Springs, Georgia, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Eric Ingraham, illustrations. The Porcupine Stew, undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
- Series IV: Personal Memorabilia
  Trophies,photographs, negatives, films, audio and visual tapes. It also includes a file with clippings andcorrespondence about her problems with the House Committee on Un-American Activities.There is also a file with important certificates from elementary school to graduate school, plusbaptismal and vaccination certificates in Box 18.
  (See also Box 15 for AVK personalhonors, biographies and awards, speeches, and papers.)
  - Trophy: Alice Keliher 3500hours, 1985 (Box 18)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058116 0
  - Trophy: Alice Keliher 3500 hours, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Trophy: Georgia College, William Heard Kilpatrick Education Center; Oct. 17, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Very old pictures, Keliher family and friends, undated (Box 18)
  - Washington Star Mess. AVK problems with the House Un-American Activities Committee, undated (Box 18)
  - Alice V. Keliher. Important certificates. From elementary school to Ph.D. Entire history of her education, plus vaccination and baptismal cert., undated (Box 18)
  - J.F.K. portrait, undated (Box 18)
  - Civic Virtue award, undated (Box 18)
  - Who's Who of American Women certificate, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Framed picture of home, undated (Box 18)
  - Wheelock College,honorary degree of doctor of science in education, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Lesley College, Doctor of Humane Letters, 1967 (Box 18)
  - New Jersey State College, honorary life membership, undated (Box 18)
  - New Jersey State College,honorary degree of doctor of letters, 1964 (Box 18)
  - Alumni Assoc. recognition, undated (Box 18)
  - Audio Tape: Mrs. Harris, age 97. 12/31/57 (speed 71/2), 1957 (Box 18)
  - Audio Tape: Leslie College meeting at Harvard. "Dangerous vacuum in today's programs. 11/22/63 (speed 3 1/2), 1963 (Box 18)
  - Audio Tape: Kilpatrick Day 4/17/62. Assembly at New Jersey State College. AVK, Dr. Kamel, Father Ford, Mr. Goodwin Watsin, Prof. Sanders, Gilligan, W H K. Parts I-I I., 1962 (Box 18)
  - Audio Tape: Ibid. Part I I I, undated (Box 18)
  - Audio Tape: Lawrence Frank dinner conversation. 75th b-day.; Jan., 1966 (Box 18)
  - Video Tape: England, contains:16 mm film--Alabama/ Montevallo houses erosion, 1939., 1939-1952 (Box 18)
  - 16mm film--2 blank tapes, The Sand Hill Story,elementary school principles and practices, West Georgia College, Hawaii workshop (summer 1952), volcano, Hawaii, Midi cable, undated (Box 18)
  - Photos and negatives--Hawaii--summer 1952 series: children, group at Kamekasueba, school,airport--flowers of Hawaii,individuals, group activities, Charleston (same child doing different things), Chinese music and costumes, Hawaiian party, Japanese dancer, school children, cabin scenes, trip around Hawaii, Mr. Chang Chun 81st birthday, President's reception, Red Parmisiana, Oci's Party. (Box 18)
  - Photos and Negs--England:41 Tessecroft, Butt-Gordon Bristol, Owen, French School, Surrey School, Elizabeth Adams, Sherburne Witton School, Scotland, Friends, Delissa, Butt and Berry, Boat trip, Postcard from Petersborough., undated (Box 18)
  - Film: New Schools for the New World. Excerpts from pictures made at school and at home by AVK, undated (Box 18)
  - Film: Visit to England (possibly), undated (Box 18)
  - Film: New schools for the New World. Another copy, undated (Box 18)
  - Film: A first grade morning--the library interest dominates but many other interests carry on., undated (Box 18)
  - Film: Up with people, undated (Box 18)
  - Film: Sightseeing Paris and Belgium, undated (Box 18)
  - Audio tape: Day in the life of teacher student reports used in article, "Mental Hygiene"; July, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 1)